Vivian Chan, Senior Software Engineer

beefballchan[at]gmail[dot]com +1 (206) 992 2842 linkedin.com/in/chan-vivian

A pragmatic, highly-motivated and eager-to-grow **jack-of-all-trades** experienced in **full stack development** in her quest for an empowering, risk-embracing, and open-minded team. Started out with a decently paid programming job, transformed through working in an inspiring team, and eventually discovered and grew my passion into crafting solutions through software.

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Expedia in Seattle, Mar 2015 - present

Expedia is the world's largest Online Travel Agent (OTA).

Led the technical directions of a customer facing product with a team of 13 multi-location engineers.

- **Designed and architected solutions** from product features, testing framework to continuous deployment pipeline, and system monitoring. Main languages used are Java, Scala, JavaScript, HTML and CSS
- Reviewed design and code for changes made by other team members and provided guidance to ensure good practices are followed.
- Initiated directions to improve and optimize the stability and efficiency of the system. E.g. Improved sandbox setup using docker, feature testing over junit test, and keep compliant with the latest company infrastructure.
- Coached and mentored team members to be engineers with ownership, confidence and autonomous. Empowered members by sharing knowledges and allowing rooms for mistakes.
- Support live-site issues on a AWS cloud backed stack by investigating through the statsd and collectd metrics and splunk logs, and by collaborating with other teams for any network/infrastructure related issues.
- Coached and evangelized engineers from within and outside of the team to practice Read-By-Refactoring skill to improve Expedia wide code quality.
- Designed, coded and support **2 tools for Expedia wide engineering team**. They are a NodeJs tool to monitor metrics of company standard application and a Java library to manage external API services like Hystrix.

Software Engineer II at Expedia in Seattle, Oct 2008 - Mar 2015

Worked in 3 different teams over 6+ years to earn a broad experience to solve different types of problems in different domains.

- Developed and shipped **high-traffic and highly-available products** including an ads management system, e-commerce website **AirAsiaGo** (https://www.airasiago.com) and tens of product features in all Expedia websites.
- **Developed, tested and shipped** cross-browser, responsive, retina-ready features and modules built with HTML5, JavaScript jQuery, etc CSS3 (LESS), SVG, sprites, etc. on top of a Spring (Java) back-end.
- Built and support deployment pipeline to deploy the stack to the AWS cloud using cloud formation template and chef script.
- Migrated and support a company wide ad serving system from doubleClick to google ads platform.

Contract Software Engineer in Test at Microsoft in Seattle, Aug 2007 - Aug 2008

Microsoft is the world's leading producer of computer software.

Developed test tools for Microsoft Exchange in C#

- Converted existing test cases to use the newly implemented test user framework.
- Owned a topology by keeping the topology up-to-date.
- Fixed bugs found in the automation tests for the current milestone.

Contract Software Engineer at Getty Images in Seattle, May 2007 - Aug 2007

Getty Images is a stock photo agency with 80 million still images.

Developed a web prototype that integrates with Adobe Bridge.

- Developed object oriented javascript classes to handle client interaction and to integrate with the callback functions.
- Altered the existing website to incorporate the scripts developed above.

Web Master at Northland Services in Seattle, Mar 2006 - May 2007

Northland Services is a container shipment company with ~100 employees.

Designed, developed and supported 3-tier external company website and internal web applications.

- Created mockup to illustrate the workflow of an internal website.
- Designed and developed data layer in SQL and business logic in ADO.NET and C#.
- Rebuilt the company website by developing web pages using HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, XML, and JavaScript.

IT Analyst at Weyerhaeuser in Seattle, Jun 2003 - Mar 2006

Weyerhaeuser is one of the world's largest private owners of timberlands.

Stewarded 5 web applications by providing support to production issues and developing enhancements.

- Developed data layer in SQL and business logic in a COM+ component.
- Developed web pages using ASP, HTML, CSS and VBScript.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computing and Software System, at University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry, at Chinese University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong